Leonardo Gonçalves de Souza

Sao Paulo, Brazil +551967632081 leogsouza@gmail.com https://leogsouza.github.io

I'm a software developer with 14+ years of experience. Currently, I'm based in São Paulo, Brazil. I mostly do Backend Development (Node.js, PHP, Java, and Golang) but I do enjoy Frontend (React, Angular and Vue.js) and Mobile (Android, React Native) too

Technical Skills

Likes: php node.js reactjs javascript linux go java cassandra spring-boot redis vuejs2 angular

Experience

Systems Analyst - GFT Technologies

Oct 2016 → Current

node.js, reactjs, angular, java, mongodb, rest, microservices, docker, apache-kafka, cassandra, redis, cqrs

Development of API Rest. Development of microservices using Java with Spring Boot and using kafka as message bus.

Developing of a application using Node.js and Angular to upload some spreadsheets for customers to monitor the sales.

Design of API's using RAML and Swagger and development of these API's using Node.js.

Web Developer - Porto Seguro

Jul 2015 \rightarrow May 2016

php, node.js, javascript, mysql, mongodb, angularjs, reactjs

Development of new functions and maintenance of the chat system used by brokers Insurance Port using NodeJS and Laravel framework (PHP).

PHP Developer - Editora Moderna

Feb 2014 \rightarrow Jun 2015

php, yii, html5, css3, javascript, mysql, mongodb

Development of a portal for customer records and selling textbooks. Development of webservices using API REST. Using Yii framework, emphasis on development using Scrum methodology.

PHP Developer – W51 Informática e Marketing php, javascript, wordpress, magento, rest, soap, mysql

Oct 2013 → Feb 2014

Development of virtual stores with Magento, server configuration for deploying, and development of customized websites using Wordpress.

Web Developer - NA5 Consultoria e Comércio

Mar 2013 → Oct 2013

php, html5, css3, javascript, yii, magento, wordpress, wordpress-plugin, wordpress-theming

Development of virtual stores with Magento, server configuration for deploying, and development of customized websites using Wordpress.

PHP Programmer – Tracersoft Tecnologia e Sistemas php, html, css, javascript, yii, magento, wordpress

May 2009 → Feb 2013

Development of systems using Yii framework. Development of virtual stores with Magento, server configuration for deploying, and development of customized websites using Wordpress.

Web Developer – Cuca Propaganda e Web php, content-management-system, wordpress, html, css

Apr 2008 → *May* 2008

Development of sites with content management. Developmento of blogs using WordPress

Education

Technologist Analyst and System Developer – Unicsul database-design, html, javascript, css, algorithm

 $2015 \rightarrow 2018$

Projects & Interests

leogsouza/remote-salary-calculator – https://github.com/leogsouza/remote-salary-calculator

 $\textit{Jan 2019} \rightarrow \textit{Current}$

Website to help developers in brazil to calculate how much will earn

leogsouza/go-chat – https://github.com/leogsouza/go-chat	Oct 2017 → Current
Example of book Go Programming Blueprints	
kanban-app – https://github.com/leogsouza/kanban-app javascript	Jul 2016 → Current
A Kanban app using React, Flux and Webpack	
time-tracker-laravel – https://github.com/leogsouza/time-tracker-laravel php	Jun 2016 → Current
Time Tracker built with Laravel and Angular	
new-eden-faces – https://github.com/leogsouza/new-eden-faces javascript	Jun 2016 → Current
mean-maps-app – https://github.com/leogsouza/mean-maps-app javascript	May 2016 → Current
angular-firebase-app – https://github.com/leogsouza/angular-firebase-app html	May 2016 → Current
Simple Angular Firebase App	
mean-todo – https://github.com/leogsouza/mean-todo javascript	May 2016 → Current
mean-todo – https://github.com/leogsouza/mean-todo javascript	May 2016 → Current
angular-routing-example – https://github.com/leogsouza/angular-routing-example html	May 2016 → Current
Simple Angular Routing Example	
simple-todos-react – https://github.com/leogsouza/simple-todos-react javascript	Apr 2016 → Current
App example using Meteor and React	

Tools First Computer: Pentium 233mmx Favorite Editor: Vs Code